N'DEAB. JACKSON

107 Teachers Way, Apt 2087, Gaithersburg, MD 20877 | (617-) 447-1003 | ndeajackson@gmail.com

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Meticulous, creative, and analytical Data Scientist with experience delivering to Corporate decision makers. A recent graduate of an Applied Data Science program, with a background in Computer Engineering, that has a multitude of tools at her disposal including being able to leverage Python, R, SQL, Excel, and Adobe Illustrator to derive valuable insights and reports that can be used in decision making processes.

EDUCATION

M.S., Applied Data Science Syracuse University Jan 2020 – Jun 2021

GPA: 3.867

C.A.S, Information Technology Management Syracuse University Jan 2020 – May 2021

GPA: 3.867

B.S., Computer Engineering Virginia State University Aug 2014 – May 2018

GPA: 3.88

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python

• R • SOL

• Design Thinking

• Adobe Illustrator

Excel

Product Demonstrations

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

IBM 2018 - Present

Technical Solution Engineer

- Acts as a technical consultant to IBM clients, IBM sales teams, and/or IBM business partners on all things IBM TRIRIGA a facilities management product that falls under the IoT brand.
- Responsible for understanding the client's business requirements, technical requirements, as well as the competitive landscape of the sale.
- Provides technical sales support that encompasses but is not limited to:
 - Collaborating with IBM sales teams to define, design, and detail the technical aspects and feasibility of proposed solutions.
 - Delivering proof of concepts/proof of technologies
 - Developing and delivering technical education
 - Supporting critical situations
 - Designing solutions
 - Answering technical questions
- Responsible for the technical accuracy of all proposed solutions

LEADERSHIP

Technical Solution Engineer Mentor – IBM

2019 - Present

 Responsible for mentoring incoming solution engineers on topics such as solution design and demonstration skills • Created an on-boarding plan that has aided a number of new hires in getting acclimated with the IBM TRIRIGA product

AWARDS, ACTIVITIES, AND EXTRACURRICULARS

Tiving by notivities, and entitle continuous and entituidad entituidad entituidad entituidad entituidad entituidad entituidad entituidad	
Trojan 10 Under 10 Award	2020
DMV Business Resource Group Co-Chair	2020 - 2021
Top Gun Sales Award	2019
Global Sales School Graduate	2018 - 2019
Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc.	2018 - Present
Kappa Mu Epsilon Math Honors Society	2016 - Present
Phenomenal Women Scholarship	2018
Virginia State University Presidential Scholarship	2014 - 2018
Virginia State University Dean's List	2014 - 2018
English Second Language Teacher – Skoura, Morocco	2017

LinkedIn Profile:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ndea-jackson/